Guide to the Lloyd Richards Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1962-2004; Series VII; 10.44; (12 boxes)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Productions
      - " Major Barbara ", 1983
        - Sample Tape 3; military music, possibilities for set change into armory / Salvation Army, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180767)
          "West Ham March", final take, sped up
        - Possible music for Major Barbara, Salvation Army, Spirit of Joy, 1983 October 3; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180775)
      - " Me Candido, preliminary themes", 1964; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1803, Item barcode 39002137180270)
      - " Medal of Honor Rag "; Country Joe and the Fish, 1982; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180809)
      - " The Moon Besieged ", 1962; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1804, Item barcode 39002137180288)
      - " Oh Babylon ", 1989; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180783)
      - " Paul Robeson ", Carl Stokes, 1978 February 9; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180791)
      - " The Piano Lesson ", 1987-1991
        A letter, dated November 20, 1991, from Christopher Bond to Richards is included. It reads in part: Dear Lloyd, Enclosed an audio tape of a recent performance of your San Brancisco "Piano Lesson" Company. Could you please listen to it and let us know how the show sounds to you?...Hope you enjoy the tape. I look forward to your comments.
        Another note is included with these audiocassettes. It reads: Lloyd - Here is the copy of the sound cues at the Hunington. I'm sorry it took so long to get to you. I would like to thank you for your help on "Piano Lesson". My experience with the show has been thoroughly enjoyable and educational. Thank you again, Scott
        - Baseball Songs, March 9; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180817)
          Contents include "The National Game", "National Anthem #3" and "Take Me Out to the Ballgame"
        - Songs, 1987 October 29; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180825)
          A list of songs is included.
          Doaker's Cooking Song
          Oh Alberta
          Texas Blues
          Travelin' Man
          Oh Lord I Want You to Help Me
        - Train Calling, Penn Station, 1988 December 30; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180833)
        - Demo, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180841)
        - Themes and Variations, original piano music, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180858)
        - Sound cues at Huntington Theatre, 1988 January 13; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180866)
        - Grunts 'n Groans, 1989 November 29; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180874)
          Contents on this audiocassette include, in part: Boy Willie, Doaker, Wining Boy, Beating the Box and alternate endings
        - Act I, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180882)
        - Untitled, side 3, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180890)
      - " A Raisin in the Sun, audition", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1805, Item barcode 39002137180296)
        Contents include: Steven Mitchell and Douglas Grant
      - " Redemption Center ", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1806, Item barcode 39002137180304)
        Includes note from "Ron" to Richards. It reads: Lloyd, This is a totally dreadful tape. If you can tell anything from it you have a magnificant set of ears. I'll play the songs for you when I come back. Take care! Ron
      - Richard III
        - Part I and II, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180924)
        - 3 and 4, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180940)
        - 5 and discussion, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180932)
        - "Incidental music by Malloy Miller", 1967; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1807, Item barcode 39002137180312)
        - "Three show tapes", 1967; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1808, Item barcode 39002137180320)
          Contents include three show tapes: music, more music (scattered close cues), ghosts
      - " Seven Guitars ", 1995, undated
        - New Submissions, 1985 December 19; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180908)
        - Goodman, scene change, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180916)
        - Sound Cues - Chicago Production, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137180957)
        - Submission, December 20; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137180965)
        - Lloyd's copy - Scene changes, 1995 December 3; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137180973)
        - "That's All Right", 1995 August 14; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137180981)
        - Band Mixes and Solo, (Goodman) guitar scene, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137180999)
        - "Lord's Prayer" examples, 1995 May 25; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181005)
          A list of artists and groups are listed. They include Staple Singers, Abyssinian Baptist Gospel Choir, Mahalia Jackson and Albertina Walker.
        - Lloyd's copy - preshow music, 1995 September 7; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181013)
      - " Timon of Athens ", 1978 March; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181054)
      - " Two Trains Running ", circa 1990, 1993
        - Preshow / Music, 1993 January; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181021)
        - Music, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181039)
        - Sources / The Electric BB King, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181047)
          In part, contents include Tyrone Davis' "Can I Change My Mind, Wilson Pickett's "Midnight Mover", BB King's "All Over Again" and "Tired of Your Jive".
        - Music / Preshow; scene shift, intermission, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181062)
          A note is attached to this audiocassette. It reads: Lloyd, The tape is missing the last two songs of the intermission. "Stay in My Corner" and "Turn It Up, Shake It Loose". There wasn't room.
      - " Uncle Vanya ", 1981
        - "Vanya" 1, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181070)
        - "Vanya" 2, undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181088)
      - " The Yearling ", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1809, Item barcode 39002137180338)
    - Interviews with Lloyd Richards
      - "Lloyd Richards interviewed by N.G. Nesmith", 2002
        Audiocassettes include a letter from Nathaniel Nesmith to Richards dated November 6, 2002. It reads: Dear Mr. Richards: Greetings. Enclosed are the tapes of the interview. I send my many thanks for allowing me to interview you. I am happy with the result and feel that the interview will represent your accomplishments. As I stated, due to commitments and a December vacation, i will not be able to transcribe the interview until early January. Please trust that I will do all within my power to place the interview in a very good publication. I will keep you abreast of the steps I am taking. I will be in touch. All the best, Nathaniel Nesmith.
        - Tape 1, Tuesday, 2002 September 24; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181104)
        - Tape 2, Wednesday, 2002 October 2; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181112)
        - Tape 3, Wednesday, 2002-10-09; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181120)
        - Tape 4, Saturday, 2002 November 2; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181138)
      - "Lloyd Richards Copy Part 1/Interviewed by Caroline Raymond", undated; 1 (Box 165, Item barcode 39002137181096)
      - "W. King/L. Richards", 2002 February 12
        - #1 and #2, Blk thea - Raisin to Now, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181146)
        - #3 and #4, blk. thea - Raisin to Now, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181153)
        - W. King/L. Richards, 2002 February 12; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181161)
      - Untitled interviews, 1983-1999
        - Lloyd Richards, Cincinnati Playhouse (Begins on B), 1998 March 2; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181179)
        - Jack O'Brien Show, 1983 June 22; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181187)
        - Geo. and LR - Jack O'Brien Show, pre-edit, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181195)
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181203)
        - Lloyd, 1992 July; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181211)
        - Lloyd Richards, J. Hamburg Show - WOR AM, 1984 July 31; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181229)
        - Interview conducted by Joan Fishman, 1994 January 31; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181237)
        - Jack O'Brien Show, Estelle Parsons - L. Richards, 1981 July; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181245)
        - Interview Carol and Lam, 1980 October 1; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181252)
        - Lloyd's interview, Ken Bush, 1993 July 28; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181260)
        - By phone: Lloyd Richards interview Robert Browning, Paramount, CA, 1985 August; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181278)
        - Interview: Lloyd Richards, 1999 April 7; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181286)
        - FSU - Headlines, 1997 February 18; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181294)
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181302)
          A letter from Ginger Rogers of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts to Lloyd Richards is included. It reads: I am enclosing a tape of the discussion presented by you and Mr. Wilson on Thursday, November 16, 1989, in the Eisenhower Theater. As we discussed, this tape was made for transcription and inclusion in the preparatory materials being sent to teachers and high school students who will attend the Thursday matinee performance on November 30, 1989. It will not be distributed or used for any other purpose without your permission. Mr. Wilson has also received a tape of the discussion. Thank you again for allowing us to tape the interview. Best wishes for continued success with the production.
        - Job/Richards and White, 1984 July 3; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181310)
        - National Playwrights Conference - P. Joffe / Connecticut Public Radio, undated; 1 (Box 166, Item barcode 39002137181328)
      - Untitled interviews, 1986-1990
        - Interview I and II, 1983 Fall; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181336)
        - Voice of America Interivew Steven Kalb, 1986 June; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181344)
          A letter to Lloyd Richards, during his time as dean of the Yale School of Drama, is included with this audiocassette. It reads: Dean Richards: Thank you for taking the time out of your busy schedule last week so that I could interview you for the "Voice of America". With graduation finally over, I hope you will be able to relax at least through part of the summer. All the best for the coming year. Respectfully, Steven D. Kalb
        - Interview - Lloyd Richards at Yale School of Drama (Interviewer-Irene Backalenick) for Theater Week Magazine, undated; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181351)
          A letter, dated April 7th, is included with this audiocassette. It reads: Enclosed is the tape of the interview we did last month for "Theater Week". My techincal skills are not all that they might be, so I apologize for the quality of the tape! it was, as always, a pleasure to meet with you and to have the interview. Sincerely, Irene B.
        - "Open Air", Lloyd Richards, December 7; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181369)
          A letter is included with this audiocassette. It reads: Dear Lloyd: Here is the tape I promised of our conversation, which I loved. As I read harold Clurman I begin to understand your respect for him. His perceptions are so rich. Merry Christmas and thanks for teaching me more about going to the theater the way I go to dinner. Faith Middleton
    - Other Recordings
      - "H and H play", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1810, Item barcode 39002137180346)
      - "Kenya, Africa", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1811, Item barcode 39002137180353)
      - "Liberian music", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1812, Item barcode 39002137180361)
      - "Music from Uganda", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1813, Item barcode 39002137180379)
        Contents include: wedding piece, flute and tidde piece, Bukoba yodel, Lango epilogue
      - "Uganda, Zambia, Kenya, Africa", 1968; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1814, Item barcode 39002137180387)
      - Various unidentified incidental music, music for research, and unidentified material, 1976-1995
        - Athol Fugard, Kch Matinee, 1985 October 13; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181377)
        - Athol Fugard, Kch Evening Show, 1985 October 13; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181385)
        - "Lorraine Hansberry: An Appreciation", NPR's Weekend Edition Sunday, reported by Cheryl Devall, 1995 May 21; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181393)
        - National Endowment for the Arts, excerpts from General Operating Support, Task Force meeting, 1976 July 8; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181401)
        - Pipes, undated; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181419)
        - Irish Music, undated; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181427)
        - Crowd, undated; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181435)
        - Gunshots, undated; 1 (Box 167, Item barcode 39002137181443)
- Oversize, 3.66; (18 boxes) + 11 broadside folders
  - Blood Knot by Athol Fugard (Series I, Production Files), 1985 (Box 168, Folder 1815)
  - Freeman by Phillip Hayes Dean (Series I, Production Files), 1987 (Box 168, Folder 1816)
  - I Had A Ball by Jerome Chodorov (Series I, Production Files), 1964 (Box 168, Folder 1817)
  - Joe Turner's Come and Gone by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1988 (Box 168, Folder 1818)
  - A Lesson From Aloes by Athol Fugard (Series I, Production Files), 1980 (Box 168, Folder 1819)
  - A Man Around the House by Joseph Julian (Series I, Production Files), circa 1966 (Box 168, Folder 1820)
  - Master Harold... and the Boys by Athol Fugard (Series I, Production Files), 1982 (Box 168, Folder 1821)
  - The Piano Lesson by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1987 (Box 168, Folder 1822)
  - The Piano Lesson by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1987-1990 (Box 168, Folder 1823)
  - A Raisin in the Sun by Lorraine Hansberry (Series I, Production Files), 1959-1960 (Box 168, Folder 1824)
  - Two Trains Running by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1991 (Box 168, Folder 1825)
  - The Yearling by Paul Osborn (Series I, Production Files), 1965-1985 (Box 168, Folder 1826-1827)
  - "Saginaw" (Series I, Production Files), 1954 (Box 168, Folder 1828)
  - "Northland Playhouse" (Series I, Production Files), 1957 (Box 168, Folder 1829)
  - Production posters (Series I, Production Files), 1957-1993 (Box 169)
  - Amen Corner by James Baldwin (Series I, Production Files), 1964-1965 (Box 170, Folder 1830)
  - The Book of Murder by Ron Cowen (Series I, Production Files), 1973-1974 (Box 170, Folder 1830a)
  - Cobb by Lee Blessing (Series I, Production Files), 1990-1991 (Box 170, Folder 1831-1832)
  - A Doll's House by Henrik Ibsen (Series I, Production Files), 1982 (Box 170, Folder 1833)
  - The Egghead by Molly Kazan (Series I, Production Files), 1957 (Box 170, Folder 1834)
  - Fences by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1985-1987 (Box 170, Folder 1835-1838)
  - Freeman by Phillip Hayes Dean (Series I, Production Files), 1972-1977 (Box 170, Folder 1839)
  - Ghosts by Henrik Ibsen (Series I, Production Files), 1965 (Box 170, Folder 1840)
  - Gold Watch by Momoko Iko (Series I, Production Files), 1974-1975 (Box 170, Folder 1841)
  - The Long Dream by Ketti Frings (Series I, Production Files), 1959-1930 (Box 170, Folder 1842)
  - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1984 (Box 170, Folder 1843)
  - Othello by William Shakespeare (Series I, Production Files), 1981 (Box 170, Folder 1844)
  - Paul Robeson by Phillip Hayes Dean (Series I, Production Files), 1977-1979 (Box 170, Folder 1845)
  - A Raisin in the Sun by Lorraine Hansberry (Series I, Production Files), 1958-1959 (Box 170, Folder 1846-1847)
  - Seven Guitars by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1996 (Box 170, Folder 1847a)
  - The Sign in Sidney Brunstein's Window by Lorraine Hansberry (Series I, Production Files), 1976 (Box 170, Folder 1847b)
  - The Suicide by Nikolai Erdman (Series I, Production Files), 1980 (Box 170, Folder 1848)
  - Timon of Athens by William Shakespeare (Series I, Production Files), 1980 (Box 170, Folder 1849)
  - Uncle Vanya by Anton Chekhov (Series I, Production Files), 1981 (Box 170, Folder 1850)
  - You Are There (Series I, Production Files), 1971 (Box 170, Folder 1851-1852)
  - "Northland Playhouse" clippings (Series I, Production Files), 1956-1957 (Box 170, Folder 1853)
  - Number not used (Box 170, Folder 1854)
  - Medal of Honor Rag by Tom Cole (Series I, Production Files), 1981-1982 (Box 171, Folder 1855)
  - The Moon Besieged by Seyril Schochen (Series I, Production Files), 1962 (Box 171, Folder 1856)
  - Afro/American Theatre Total Arts Foundation (Series II, Professional Files), 1977 (Box 171, Folder 1857)
  - Plaques and objects (Series II, Professional Files), 1992 (Box 172)
  - Plaques and objects (Series II, Professional Files), 1992 (Box 173)
  - Plaques and objects (Series II, Professional Files), 1986 (Box 174)
  - Certificates (Series II, Professional Files), 1962-1998 (Box 175, Folder 1858-1866)
  - Certificates (Series II, Professional Files), 1962-1998 (Box 176, Folder 1867-1869)
  - "Tribute to Lloyd Richards: The Man and his Work" at Yale University on October 20, 1998 (Series II, Professional Files) (Box 177)
  - Certificates (Series II, Professional Files), 1962-1998 (Box 178, Folder 1870)
  - Number not used (Box 178, Folder 1871)
  - Various NPC photographs (Series III, Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center ), undated (Box 178, Folder 1872)
  - Publicity (Series III, Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center ), 1971-1997 (Box 178, Folder 1873-1877)
  - Dyson College Lectures in the Humanities (Series II, Professional Files), 1998 November 8 (Box 179, Folder 1878)
  - Illustrations of various people, including Richards (Series II, Professional Files), 1991 (Box 179, Folder 1879-1880)
  - Publicity on Richards (Series II, Professional Files), 1952-2006, undated (Box 180, Folder 1881-1893)
  - Publicity on Richards (Series II, Professional Files), 1952-2006, undated (Box 181, Folder 1894-1909)
  - Publicity on Richards and Athol Fugard (Series II, Professional Files), 1984-1990 (Box 182, Folder 1910-1911)
  - Publicity on Richards and August Wilson (Series II, Professional Files), 1990 (Box 182, Folder 1912)
  - Publicity on Richards and others (Series II, Professional Files), 1979 (Box 182, Folder 1913)
  - With unidentified friends (Series V, Photographs), undated (Box 183, Folder 1914)
  - With James Earl Jones (Series V, Photographs), 1979 (Box 183, Folder 1915)
  - By Paul Penders (Series V, Photographs), 1984 (Box 183, Folder 1916)
  - Cobb (Series V, Photographs), 1989 (Box 183, Folder 1917)
  - Fences (Series V, Photographs), 1987 (Box 183, Folder 1918-1919)
  - Unidentified productions (Series V, Photographs), undated (Box 183, Folder 1920-1924)
  - Unidentified framed portrait (Series V, Photographs), undated (Box 184)
  - Framed artwork (Series VI, Personal Papers), undated (Box 185)
  - Russian poster (Series III, Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center), undated (Box Bsd, Folder 1925)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, folder 1926)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, folder 1927)
  - Event poster (Series III, Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Center), undated (Box Bsd, folder 1928)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files), 1981-1988 (Box Bsd, folder 1929)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files), 1980-1990 (Box Bsd, folder 1930)
  - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom by August Wilson (Series I, Production Files), 1984 (Box Bsd, folder 1931)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, Folder 1932)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, Folder 1933)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, Folder 1934)
  - Various production posters (Series I, Production Files) (Box Bsd, Folder 1935)